# VERA SILVA



My name is Vera and I'm 34 years old. I have been teaching early years for almost 10 years now. Currently I'm also accumulating my early years class with nursery manager position.

It is with a great interest that I am presenting my CV for nursery manager or early years teacher position. I am interest about this position and I believe that my profile could be the perfect fit for your team.

I am a very driven person who must enjoy working with small children. I also take pleasure in providing support staff with all the tools they need to succeed. I have worked with children with all ages, from just few months up to six years.

I have recently gone through an interview in MOE and being approved as manager in my current job. However, I'm looking for a new challenge. I am available for an interview at a time convenient for yourselves to allow me to discuss my experience and qualifications further.

#### **EDUCATION**

**EARLY CHILDHOOD EDUCATION BACHELOR DEGREE** – PIAGET INSTITUTE (ESCOLA SUPERIOR DE EDUCACAO JEAN PIAGET) – SEPTEMBER 2005 TO JULY 2009

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### ❖ NURSERY MANAGER - Deira Private Nursery / Dubai - September 2019 to Present

- To supervise in an active manner the day-to day running of the centre including staff and care and activities of children.
- To ensure that the state and standard of premises and equipment is of the highest quality and conforms to EYFS guidelines.
- To ensure that all staff are aware and adhere to the daily routines and policies.
- Formulate and supervise the effective teaching of the curriculum and consult with and communicate with teachers and parents as to goals and Outcomes.
- Develop and maintain ongoing and effective communication between parents and staff to ensure that there is a shared perception of quality.
- Establish and maintain an effective process for consultation and evaluation of the service.
- To establish and maintain effective systems to monitor, review and evaluate services.
- To implement components business plan and marketing.
- To operate within agreed budgets and collate and complete accurate financial records
- To ensure children's' records are up-to-date.
- To work with all staff to ensure that there is effective liaison with the parents over the care of their children, a smooth induction for new children and parents.
- To write and implement policies and procedures in consultation with the Board of governors and principal.
- Co-ordinate the allocation of places and maintain waiting lists.
- To respect and maintain confidentiality in respect of the families at all times.

#### ❖ YEAR ONE TEACHER/ Deira Private School / Dubai - August 2018 to August 2019

- Develop an early years friendly approach in year one.
- Plan hands on activities.
- Organise and develop a continuous provision.

# ❖ EARLY YEARS TEACHER/ Deira Private School / Dubai - August 2015 to July 2018

- Plan and implement a dynamic curriculum with fun, hand-on activities.

### NURSERY TEACHER/ Nursery "O Portugal dos pequeninos / Portugal -March 2010 to July 2015

- Responsible for a class of 18 children and for covering all areas of learning and development.

#### EARLY YEARS MANAGEMENT/ LEADERSHIP TRAINING/WORKSHOPS

Safer recruitment for international schools	Educare	2020
Reflective Practice in Early Years	Early Years alliance	2020
Managing Early Years Inspection	Early Years alliance	2020
Characteristics of effective leaders	Early Years alliance	2020
The importance of self-evaluation	Early Years alliance	2020
Supporting staff wellbeing in schools	Educare	2020

#### EARLY YEARS TEACHING TRAINING/ WORKSHOPS

Supporting Early Language Development	Early Years alliance	2020
Speech, Language and Communication	Early Year alliance	2020
Theories underpinning EYFS	Early Years alliance	2020
Understanding and addressing behaviour in the Early Years	Early Years alliance	2020
Improving children's learning through play	Early Years alliance	2020
Characteristics of Effective teaching and learning	Early Years alliance	2020
Continuous provision	EYES Certificate	2016
Early Years Foundation Stage Course	NMT Training	2015
-	·	
Understanding the Revised Early Years Foundation Stage	CACHE ELP - Level 2 Award	2015
An Enabling Learning Environment	CACHE ELP	2015
The Role of the Key worker in Early Years Settings	MNT Training Certificate	2015
Touchpoints Early Care and Education Training Program Certificate	Dr. Brazelton/ Gomes Pedro Foundation	2015
Observation & Planning for Early Years Practitioners	MNT Training Certificate	2015
Cultural Awareness	CACHE ELP	2015
Children's Food Safety and Nutrition for Early Years Settings	Level 3 OCN - MNT Training Certificate	2015
The Reggio Emilia Approach: principles and practices.	Piaget Institute Certificate	2014
Right to Education since the birth	APEI - Early Childhood Teachers Association Certificate, Portugal)	2012

#### ENGLISH LANGUAGE TRAINING/ WORKSHOPS

JOLLY PHONICS	Jolly Phonics	2019
Understanding early literacy for primary	British Council Online Course	2019
Engaging with pronunciation – techniques and activities	British Council Online Course	2019

#### SPECIAL EDUCATION NEEDS TRAINING/ WORKSHOPS

Understanding Special Education Needs	British Council Online Course	2019
Supporting Children with special needs	NMT Training	2015

#### CHILD PROTECTION/ SAFEGUARDING TRAINING/ WORKSHOPS

Equality and Inclusion in Early Years settings	Early Years alliance	2020
Adverse Childhood Experiences (ACEs)	Educare	2020
Overcoming Loneliness	Educare	2020
Child Neglect for international schools	Educare	2020
First Aid for international schools	Educare	2020
Use of reasonable force in schools	Educare	2020
First Aid, CPR & AED Training	American Safety & Health Institute	2020
Mental Wellbeing in Children and Young People	Educare	2020
Child Protection for international schools	Educare	2019
Understanding Child Protection	British Council Online course	2019
Safeguarding in the Early Years	Level 2 - MNT Training Certificate	2015

## EDUCATION FOR SUSTAINABLE DEVELOPMENT TRAINING/ WORKSHOPS

Education for Sustainable Development CPD	TES Institute and WWF	2010

#### LANGUAGES

ENGLISH	ADVANCED	
PORTUGUESE	NATIVE	
SPANISH	INTERMEDIATE	